export const quizQuestions = {
  totalQuestions: 5,
  questions: [
    {
      id: 1,
      question: "W którym roku urodziła się Maria Skłodowska-Curie?",
      translateQuestion: "In which year was Maria Sklodowska-Curie born?",
      answers: ["1888", "1867", "1840", "1853"],
      translateAnswers: ["1888", "1867", "1840", "1853"],
      correctAnswer: "1867",
      translateCorrectAnswer: "1867",
    },
    {
      id: 2,
      question: "Ile Nagród Nobla otrzymała Maria Skłodowska-Curie?",
      translateQuestion:
        "How many Nobel Prizes has Marie Sklodowska-Curie received?",
      answers: ["3", "2", "1", "4"],
      translateAnswers: ["3", "2", "1", "4"],
      correctAnswer: "2",
      translateCorrectAnswer: "2",
    },
    {
      id: 3,
      question: "Mężem Marii Skłodowskiej-Curie był:",
      translateQuestion: "The husband of Maria Sklodowska-Curie was:",
      answers: ["Jacques Curie", "Jan Curie", "Pierre Curie", "Paul Curie"],
      translateAnswers: [
        "Jacques Curie",
        "Jan Curie",
        "Pierre Curie",
        "Paul Curie",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "Pierre Curie",
      translateCorrectAnswer: "Pierre Curie",
    },
    {
      id: 4,
      question: "Maria Skłodowska-Curie stworzyła:",
      translateQuestion: "Maria Sklodowska-Curie created:",
      answers: ["promieniotwórczość", "radiochemię", "chemię", "radiację"],
      translateAnswers: [
        "radioactivity",
        "radiochemistry",
        "chemistry",
        "radiation",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "radiochemię",
      translateCorrectAnswer: "radiochemistry",
    },
    {
      id: 5,
      question:
        "Jak nazywają się pierwiastki, które odryła Maria Skłodowska-Curie?",
      translateQuestion:
        "What are the names of the elements discovered by Maria Sklodowska-Curie?",
      answers: [
        "frans i cez",
        "rad i polon",
        "kopernik i promet",
        "kiur i einstein",
      ],
      translateAnswers: [
        "franium and cesium",
        "radium and polonium",
        "copernicus and promethium",
        "curium and einstein",
      ],
      correctAnswer: "rad i polon",
      translateCorrectAnswer: "radium and polonium",
    },
  ],
};
